<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>daniel.industries</title>
 <link href="http://daniel.industries/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://daniel.industries/"/>
 <updated>2020-11-29T19:42:50-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://daniel.industries</id>
 <author>
   <name>Daniel Miller</name>
   <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Tweaking the Setup</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/28/tweaking-the-setup/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-28T23:43:41-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/28/tweaking-the-setup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/pop_os/comments/k1f4nj/making_a_10yearlong_macbook_owner_switch_to_pop_os/&quot;&gt;“Making a 10-year-long MacBook owner switch to Pop OS”&lt;/a&gt; I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/themagicalmammal/howtopopbuntu&quot;&gt;this Pop_OS setup guide&lt;/a&gt; from which I stole or was inspired to change some things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost I finally got PulseEffects equalizer working thanks to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/themagicalmammal/howtopopbuntu#audio-tools&quot;&gt;audio tools&lt;/a&gt; section and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu-mate.community/t/pulse-effects-equaliser-not-working-in-20-04lts/21929&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;! On the Mac, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globaldelight.com/boom/&quot;&gt;Boom&lt;/a&gt; and it was towards the top of the list of things I missed. I like this PulseEffects equalizer better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/11/pulse-equalizer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed a few more Gnome extensions but ended up only using &lt;em&gt;dynamic panel transparency&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/11/tweaks-with-panel.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs/&quot;&gt;Starship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/11/terminal-with-starship.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed FiraCode Nerd Font via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdfonts.com/font-downloads&quot;&gt;Nerd Fonts&lt;/a&gt; and am now using it wherever I use monospaced fonts. Not sure about this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed my theme up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome-look.org/p/1441725/&quot;&gt;Skeuos&lt;/a&gt; as seen in the above screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>FrontPage</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/27/frontpage/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-27T00:24:14-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/27/frontpage</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Microsoft FrontPage. The mere mention of that name is making most (if not all) of you seasoned web devs groan. “FrontPage was utter rubbish from dark ages of GeoCities” you say. “Everything it touched was ruined with horrific output and proprietary nonsense!” And yes, it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But…FrontPage as a concept. As a dream of what could have been, and a window into what was. Letting the typical home user at the time create websites, express creativity, and conquer the world by storm, all without being forced to learn HTML or CSS or JavaScript…In that regard, FrontPage couldn’t be beat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about why Microsoft FrontPage was for a brief period of time the ultimate content creation tool of the Internet, and why it later fell from grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/&quot;&gt;FrontPage: The Good, The Bad, and The Ugly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got my start in tech teaching Microsoft Office, HTML, Photoshop (version 6!), and FrontPage (what must have been version 1.1 or FrontPage 98) at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Horizons_Computer_Learning_Centers&quot;&gt;New Horizons&lt;/a&gt; franchise in South Florida. It was a bizarre experience in the middle of a bizarre time in my life. I had just graduated from the University of Arizona. In the last few months of my time in Tucson, I had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Excommunication&quot;&gt;excommunicated&lt;/a&gt; from the church around which I had centered my life for the previous four years. I moved to South Florida and set about trying to find employment. I didn’t have a plan except to get married. My (now ex) wife and I settled in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunrise,_Florida&quot;&gt;Sunrise&lt;/a&gt;. I got a job teaching drums at a worse-for-wear music school for kids and briefly as an interim worship leader at a Baptist church. I was fired from the latter after three months—that’s a different blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t even lay eyes on the ocean for the first six months I lived in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I stumbled into the job at New Horizons. Turnover at that franchise—and I would assume most franchises—was intense. That made getting a job there pretty easy. Keeping the job, on the other hand, was not. Onboarding was: there was a small room in the back with a few folding tables with computers on them. I was shown to that room and given a coursebook (the same book students received) and told to learn it that day. I was to teach that course the following day. It was probably Microsoft Word. Maybe Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to wear a suit every day. Besides the classrooms where the actual training occurred, there was another room full of cubicles where the inside salespeople cold-called all day long. I assume that their onboarding experience was even bleaker than mine. It was classic &lt;em&gt;Glengarry Glen Ross&lt;/em&gt; style sales management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three basic skills required: learn fast, be good in front of a room full of people, and think fast on one’s feet. Fortunately, I had those skills. I didn’t know I had them going in, but looking back I can see that I did. And I was right at the front of that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&quot; title=&quot;the Dunning–Kruger effect is a cognitive bias in which people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability&quot;&gt;Dunning–Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt; curve, so I didn’t know how little I knew about the actual subjects I was teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took to the graphic design and web stuff. If you could learn it, you got to teach it, especially if it was a little bit harder material like Photoshop and FrontPage. This was 1998, and most people barely used the web, let alone understood how it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as that article explains, FrontPage actually made it make sense. I took my new skills and began creating web pages for myself. I hosted them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_GeoCities&quot;&gt;GeoCities&lt;/a&gt;, as one did, or on the free hosting provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BellSouth_Telecommunications&quot; title=&quot;BellSouth&quot;&gt;my ISP at the time&lt;/a&gt;. I eventually graduated to writing HTML and CSS by hand using the HTML editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML-Kit&quot;&gt;HTML-Kit&lt;/a&gt;. I only ended up spending about three months at New Horizons. I was offered a real tech job, where I learned Visual Basic and some C++. Later I learned ColdFusion and PHP…then C#, Java, ActionScript, JavaScript, Ruby…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Podcast Roundup</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/24/podcast-roundup/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-24T08:26:50-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/24/podcast-roundup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since a few podcasts all hit home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andrewskotzko.com/natalie-nagele-building-a-people-first-company-at-wildbit/&quot;&gt;Make Things That Matter #30 – Natalie Nagele: Building a people-first company at Wildbit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…the way I look at it is the entrepreneur [does] a thing because [they] want to prove a point. And I think the business person is there to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is this business you’re building? What’s the core purpose? …if the core purpose is just making money…[there are] cheaper ways to make money…you can work at Facebook and make a lot…if money is the only driver owning a business is not necessarily…the best approach…statistically that’s not your best bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…when it’s been most fun is when we’ve reflected on who we are as humans, and then applied that to what we want out of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/5w4CR2vNRWYPlq4YvdAnKf?si=jJ_aYAFwTWGiiqHDlLocxw&quot;&gt;Word from the Herd – The Optimism Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One of the coolest things we can do as a leader is to create an environment that is enriching and where people can grow and prosper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Assume everything will get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hopeinsource.com/process/&quot;&gt;Hope in Source – Technology as Process (Maggie Appleton)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I do love all the ways that it shows up in modern culture outside of any religious connotation. I mean, when you talk about the self help industry or especially the obsession around habit forming. You know, the behavioral sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And even right, like bootstrapping and hustle culture, it all just reeks of Protestant work ethic. All of it, right. Go into the incubator and you have to sleep three hours a night and just get your startup going. You know, what are people chasing except for some sense of salvation at the end where they think, well, if I do this, I’m gonna have been ethically in the right by the end of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And in the capitalist cosmology of this system, the reward is money instead of salvation. If we’re going to call American capitalism a religious belief system in itself, which wouldn’t be too difficult to argue, it is that your eternal salvation is you become a millionaire and buy a Ferrari. It’s not a millionaire anymore. Now it has to be a billionaire, you know, inflation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Do You Lament Being a Generalist?</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/16/do-you-lament-being-a-generalist/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-16T23:57:03-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/16/do-you-lament-being-a-generalist</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mlBnrx5Z3Ww&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whoisnnamdi.com/never-enough-developers/&quot;&gt;Why We Will Never Have Enough Software Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Software engineers never escape the skill-change vortex, even many years into their careers. Experienced engineers must learn and adopt technologies that didn’t even exist when they started out. Developers must constantly retool themselves…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the quickest learners are also the quickest dropouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To understand why, think back to the model we just outlined. Quick learners accumulate human capital faster than their slower peers, which means they have the most to lose when certain skills or abilities fall out of favor. In fact, the return to being a fast learner is higher in jobs with low rates of skill change because the learnings can compound over time instead of dwindle in relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;High-ability workers are faster learners, in all jobs. However, the relative return to ability is higher in careers that change less, because learning gains accumulate.
Said another way, the opportunity cost of working in a rapidly-changing field is highest for the best learners. This creates immense pressure to drop out of software engineering and other fast-changing careers into more stable roles and industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…rapid technological change can lead to a short shelf life for technical skills. This tradeoff between technology-specific and general skills is an important consideration for policymakers and colleges seeking to educate the workers of today, while also building the skills of the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the majority of the last decade, as my technical skills have become mostly obsolete and my business and management skills have not proportionally compensated, I’ve often found myself under waves of impostor syndrome. It’s as if, at 45, I’m just now experiencing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect#:~:text=In%20the%20field%20of%20psychology,recognize%20their%20lack%20of%20ability.&quot;&gt;Dunning-Kruger’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;valley of despair&lt;/em&gt;, not as it relates to a specific skill, but as it relates to my entire life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/11/Dunning-Kruger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I watched the Adam Savage video above, as he referred to his “quiver full of arrows”, all I could think was my arrows are broken and dull. The Nnamdi Iregbulem article confirmed my suspicions. I’m no longer qualified to accomplish the technical tasks I spent most of my career training myself to do properly. The new tasks are, by comparison, nauseatingly un-quantifiable. There’s no &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspec.info/&quot;&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cypress.io/&quot;&gt;Cypress&lt;/a&gt; to let me know if I’m doing it right. There’s just going out of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, being a leader doesn’t mean understanding minefields more than others, it just means being the most willing to first step on a land mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/11/call-it-a-draw.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;small postscript&quot;&gt;^ middle-age vs life ^&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>When I Think About the Ways So Many People Are Denying the Reality of This Pandemic I Want to Cry</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/14/when-i-think-about-the-ways-so-many-people-are-denying-the-reality-of-this-pandemic-dot-dot-dot-i-want-to-cry/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-14T07:38:53-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/14/when-i-think-about-the-ways-so-many-people-are-denying-the-reality-of-this-pandemic-dot-dot-dot-i-want-to-cry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m usually not one to quote Vice but the intro to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgqqa4/how-to-protect-your-grandparents-from-covid-over-the-holidays-christmas&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; was emotionally on the nose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A terrible truth about 2020: We can choose to do the right things, often at great personal cost, but other people—even people we care about, including our own relatives!—might be completely disinclined to make safe or wise choices. And when that happens, they aren’t just threatening themselves and others in the abstract sense; they are threatening people we know personally and feel a particular sense of duty to protect, and who we would feel like we failed if we didn’t do everything in our power to intervene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You’re right that this isn’t an uncommon spot to be in this year, and I’m sad and angry for you and for everyone who has to both make the decision to not see elderly relatives for what could be their last holiday, and—as if that weren’t enough!!!—convince their family members that the coronavirus is indeed a real threat. I know we’ve been at this for months now, but I’m freshly furious thinking about how outrageous it is that at least 225,000 people in the U.S. have died from COVID-19 complications, and there are still folks out here acting like it’s not that serious, or that flying to Mexico or going to a wedding right now or putting their own loved ones (and selves!!) at risk is a cool and fine thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be quite honest, I was simply not prepared for the ways in which facts would cease to matter in my adult life. When I think about the ways so many people are denying the reality of this pandemic, or the fact that the core belief of the ever-growing and fully delusional QAnon cohort is that prominent Democrats are trafficking children in order to kill them and then drink their blood and there’s kind of no way to convince them otherwise, I want to cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Have a Meeting if You're Optimizing for Speed</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/11/08/have-a-meeting-if-youre-optimizing-for-speed/"/>
   <updated>2020-11-08T23:03:45-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/11/08/have-a-meeting-if-youre-optimizing-for-speed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/igrigorik/status/1324831467638149120&quot;&gt;Ilya Grigorik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When making a decision, have a meeting if you’re optimizing for speed, write first if optimizing for quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good decisions require clear thinking. Clear thinking requires sitting with the problem to understand it deeply, which writing forces you to confront what decision is being made, the tradeoffs, and downstream second+ order impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Synchronous decision making optimizes for speed, guided by intuition, pattern matching, and mental heuristics. It seems effective because it feels efficient, but it does not yield same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time to Think</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/10/28/time-to-think/"/>
   <updated>2020-10-28T06:38:59-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/10/28/time-to-think</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Both of my daily email “readings”—the Daily Stoic and Richard Rohr—were about stillness this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://email.cac.org/t/ViewEmail/d/B492D0F8C8B4BD0E2540EF23F30FEDED/5D4D295FD8D5D838F039C523302FD418&quot;&gt;Rohr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our true nature is stillness,&lt;br /&gt;
The Source from which we come.&lt;br /&gt;
The deep listening of pure contemplation&lt;br /&gt;
Is the path to stillness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Thomas Keating, “Stillness”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dailystoic.com/theres-a-time-to-make-and-a-time-to-manage/&quot;&gt;Daily Stoic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So how do you make good out of an indefinite quarantine? Well one easy way is to use this time to think. Take Seneca in his exiles as your inspiration. Or Musonius and Epictetus in theirs. How did they spend it? Writing. Reading. They were thinking and planning. They came out wiser, with a clearer sense of what was important in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your employees are not going to come up with your business’ five year plan for you—only you can do that. Your publisher is not going to write your book for you. Your sales assistant isn’t going to come up with your next great sales strategy. They’re not going to invest in relationships for you. They’re not going to help you find inspiration to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You have to do that. And today is a great day to do that. Now is a time to make. To think. To reflect. To do what only you can do. To cultivate that stillness—because stillness is the key to insights and creativity and all the things you’re going to need to dig yourself out of this hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good thing my meditation practice is back(ish). (I’m still really bad at meditation.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was actually thinking as I poured my coffee this morning (prior to reading these) that there’s consistently been this dilemma in organizations I’ve been a part of, where leaders want their staff to think more strategically—or even just more tactically—but said staff is far too busy just trying to keep up with the abitious plans of said leaders to take time to think. This often applies even at the highest level of an organization, where even directors, vice presidents, and CEOs have their time fully allocated to meetings and batting away emails and Slack messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should we try to fix this, and if so, how do we go about solving this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a “maybe” answer, which is higher-ups in an organization should be doing the strategic thinking and others necessarily need to busy themselves with tactics and execution. I’m of half a mind to agree with this point of view, as I’ve always been on the side of “actions speak louder than words” and the mindset that the best way to move a business forward is with getting working code in front of actual users. There’s a necessary balance, however, as without a destination in the distance the boat will simply wander the sea. The C-level people at organizations I admire do seem to share some habits of stillness. It’s hard, however, to quantify the value of stillness. Especially to the productivity bean-counter in one’s own head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also the “absolutely” answer. Everyone in the org needs to be thinking deeply about the problems of the business. True innovation doesn’t come from the top, it comes from those closest to the product and the customers. I’m not sure where I personally stand on this one, but I know one thing: founders I’ve worked with over the last 10+ years have all wished their employees would think more strategically about the business. And we have an entire market of tools and content that prove this isn’t confined to my experience. OKRs; quarterly goals; &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/shapeup&quot;&gt;shaped pitches&lt;/a&gt;. Most of these require everyone in the org to &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; think tactically about how to best use their time. How does one do that when you’re just trying to wrap up &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; quarter’s goals? (Not to mention the five extra urgent projects that landed on your plate after the quarter was planned.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One potential answer is to create more space–have fewer meetings, say “no” to more random sales requests, plan to do less than you would really like. But just having the space to think is not enough. Firstly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson's_law&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s Law&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; exert itself—or at least one of its corollaries: &lt;em&gt;Work complicates to fill the available time&lt;/em&gt;. Secondly, and this &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be the solution to the former, people need to learn (be trained) to use that space appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m struggling with all of this personally, obviously, or I wouldn’t be writing down these thoughts. Here are some of the practical ideas I’ve had for trying to cultivate this type of thinking, when looking through a mindfulness/stillness lens, such as was presented to me this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a clearly communicated vision&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultivate mindfulness
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reading clubs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provide a meditation app subscription, or yoga classes, or whatever&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Psychological safety to share learnings from one’s practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultivate reading and writing that relates to the vision&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultivate rapid feedback within an environment of psychological safety&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule time for all of this and provide automatic feedback mechanisms
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Journaling&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;RFCs, including scheduling time for people to read and respond to RFCs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Training on how to write, specifically how to write with the org as your audience. Templates.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultivate participation from those typically silent. If you are typically a loud “voice in the room”, pause before speaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final thought is one of my favorite things I’ve ever read about leadership. It was a random tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;one the largest indicators i’ve seen of effective leadership is one that is actually a result of a visible absence, which is to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;leaders spend a lot of time sitting quietly with uncomfortable feelings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ag_dubs/status/999332132530114562&quot;&gt;ashley williams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Century</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/10/24/century/"/>
   <updated>2020-10-24T23:39:25-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/10/24/century</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/4238673542&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/10/strava8614156335213838786.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pandemic hit our shores and my employer, like many, sent us all home to work, I started riding more. I normally do ride more in the summer after the kids are out of school, but with the kids home from school as well, the earlier-in-the-year-than-normal schedule change opened up a lot more riding opportunities. I think I’ve ridden more in 2020 than I have since Milo was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the summer I decided I wanted to do another unsupported century ride (100 miles). I made a plan to increase milage gradually over the course of many weekends. That plan didn’t quite pan out. I started to get really fatigued towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The date for the century had been set, however, and I had a determined friend going with who I knew would not let me off the hook. After last weekend’s riding went terribly, I took most of the week off. I slept a lot more than usual (although my usual isn’t much, so that means 8 hours a night instead of 6-7).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather looked to be perfect. 40-something-Fahrenheit moving up into the 50s. Light wind, especially for this time of year. I ended up in knee warmers, arm warmers, and a light vest for almost the entire ride. I only stowed the vest away towards the very end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d been scoping out some new roads south of the city for a while, but still hit some new-to-us, beautiful country roads today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My back was my main concern and my main source of pain. I took two Advils–one at each of our stops–one at mile 30 and one at mile 70.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My legs started to lose power towards the end, but I made it! They’re very sore now. Tomorrow will be interesting. I just took a third Advil. 😬&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Contemplating What Is Real</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/10/23/fake/"/>
   <updated>2020-10-23T07:24:30-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/10/23/fake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What about the perfectly secure dudes I dumped because I disliked the broken machinery of their mediocre minds? I almost married a man whose entire personality was a sitcom with the couch in the middle of the room. Was it anxious of me to believe I could sit on that couch and listen to that laugh track until I was dead? Was it avoidant of me to finally exit those paper-thin walls in search of someone a little less scripted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now the pope is a pragmatist who likes gay marriage and the supreme court is packed with fantasy-loving ghouls who hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not morally aberrant to question this waking nightmare, along with every single principle and tradition that sprang from its chaotic core. It’s not unhinged to stop in the middle of this dreamscape and proclaim it unsafe, unwell, unfit for human consumption. It’s not disordered to love and hate a person at the same time. Nothing could be more rational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask Molly: &lt;a href=&quot;https://askmolly.substack.com/p/fake&quot;&gt;Fake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To many people, contemplation is an old-fashioned word, but it simply means the deliberate seeking of God by an inner dialogue. The soul grows closer to God through our willingness to detach from the passing self, the tyranny of feelings, the addiction to self-image, and the false promises of culture. It is a journey into the nothingness of true faith, where the ordinary rules of thinking, managing, explaining, and fixing up the smaller self do not apply. Contemplation shouldn’t be used to spiritually bypass what is real, harmful, or unjust in our lives or the world around us. However, with steady practice it will eventually give us the ability to stay present to what is, and meet it with wisdom, compassion, and courage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure that most people in the Western world have ever really met the person who they themselves really are. Most of us have lived our lives with a steady stream of ideas, images, and feelings that we cling to–thinking they are our very essence. But in reality, at that level, I don’t have the idea; the idea has me. I don’t have the feeling; the feeling has me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At every moment, all our life long, we identify ourselves either with our thoughts, our self-image, or our feelings. We have to find a way to get beyond those things…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We long for great-souled people who can hold the chaos together within themselves–and give us the courage to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://email.cac.org/t/ViewEmail/d/5D0B88E6AA10EBDE2540EF23F30FEDED/5D4D295FD8D5D838F039C523302FD418&quot;&gt;What the Mystics Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost 9 am but it’s still dark outside due to the thunderclouds that brew overhead. I can tell how much it has rained this morning because there was a Tupperware container left on the table outside my window. Well over an inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to go on a quick, easy ride this morning. I’m planning on riding 100 miles tomorrow. My body has been failing me lately, so I’ve only ridden once this week and need to make sure the bike is ready and my body is loosened up. I am hoping the rain stops later this morning so I can do a quick lap of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of riding, I managed to catch up on some emails. I actually read some of the newsletters I’m subscribed to. I’m pretty picky about these things, but I do enjoy the ones that make me think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in a very small (three of us) group sharing our fiction with one another. Well, two of us are, at least. Well, one of us, really. Until this morning, it had been over a month since I’d sent anything to them. I caught up on a month’s worth of weekly emails from the consistent one of the group, and then sent the second half of a short story I finished recently. I’ve actually finished two short stories in the last month. Now I’m stalled out again. I’m trying to write 50,000 words worth of short stories by the end of the year. I’m at just under 35,000. I need to write 226 words every day to make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of life is living within tension. I needed to ride my bike this morning but am glad to have caught up on some neglected correspondence and reading. But I’m also terribly behind on many other projects I could have spent the first two hours of my morning working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People I love dearly are voting for Trump. We live absolutely dripping with privilege but with a nagging, constant fear of losing it all. We consider ourselves moral creatures, but we pollute the earth with abandon, and steal from the poor, and send our money to the rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always enjoyed the idea of artistic contemplation. Art both injects and resolves that tension of existence. The people I’ve always admired live artistically within the tension. The ones I’ve disdained live in ignorance of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…he lets rain fall on the righteous and the unrighteous alike” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew+5%3A45&amp;amp;version=ISV&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Emotional Journey of Creating Anything</title>
   <link href="http://daniel.industries/2020/10/19/the-dark-swamp-of-despair/"/>
   <updated>2020-10-19T22:36:18-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://daniel.industries/2020/10/19/the-dark-swamp-of-despair</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/2020/10/dark-swamp-of-despair.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2020/10/dark-swamp-of-despair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to reverse image search on this to find its origin, to no avail. I found it &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Siunami/the-dark-swamp-of-despair-b20d584327f9&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;https://infodistillery.com/learn/&quot;&gt;How to Learn: Lifelong Learning&lt;/a&gt;, via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.email/stephenpa/archive/mighty-minds-club-newsletter-15-the-focus-edition/&quot;&gt;Mighty Minds Club Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
